appsheet.com 2019-11-16

# Privacy Policy - AppSheet

_Last updated: August 16, 2019_

We care about and respect the privacy of your data.

The AppSheet service asks for and stores some of your personal contact information that you provide to us voluntarily, specifically your email address and any additional information you may provide to us voluntarily. Our service also collects and analyses service usage data across all its users. This privacy policy explains what data is recorded in each category and how this data is used.

## Personal Information

You provide personally identifiable information when you sign up for our service. When you sign up via a third-party authentication provider (like Google or Dropbox), our service retrieves and saves some information about you from the provider. The specific information is controlled by the authentication provider and by the permissions you approve when you sign up. In particular, our service retrieves your email address.

In addition to the information we collect when you sign up, you may voluntarily provide us with additional personal information. For example: 

  * Your place of employment, when you complete a sales form on our website. 
  * Addresses, telephone numbers, additional email addresses, and other personally identifiable information you provide to us through any sales and marketing forms available on our website. This type of information helps us improve our business relationship with you. 

**Y** **our personally identifiable information will not be sold or rented to third parties in a way that identifies you as an individual.** In the event that we are acquired by another company, your personally identifiable information may be part of the assets transferred to the acquiring party.

We may share anonymized, aggregated order information with third parties as a way to understand, explain, and analyze our business (e.g., X% of our users used feature Y).

## Application Data

The data that your applications collect and use reside in a third-party storage provider (e.g., Google Drive, Dropbox, etc.). Our service does not persist this data. However, in order to improve performance, we may temporarily cache data, images, and other files.

In order to interact with your data, our service maintains authentication (OAuth) tokens that allow our software to act "on your behalf" to read and write data. These tokens are securely stored along with your personal information.

Our mobile client is designed to work offline. As a result, all application data that the client uses can be cached locally. This data is typically not visible to other applications on the mobile device. There is one exception to this: photos taken by the user on the device are also stored in the camera roll on the device, where they are visible to other applications. This is done to make photograph management convenient for users.

## Usage Data

Our service uses browser session cookies and browser local storage to maintain user session state. This helps to speed up user login. You can set your browser to disable cookies and local storage, but this will significantly compromise or disable product usability.

Our service logs usage information in encrypted log files, including the features you accessed on our site and standard browser-provided information. We use this information not only to debug issues and problems, but also to learn aggregated patterns across all our users and thereby improve our service.

Our service may send notifications via email and other notification mechanisms. We may employ clear gifs to track the effectiveness of our emails.

We may utilize multiple third-party products and services to help understand and analyze usage data on our site. Currently, we use Google Analytics, Hubspot, Intercom, and MixPanel, which collect usage data from your browser/app as you use our site. Each such third-party service has its own privacy policy. AppSheet commits to review third parties that receive information from AppSheet to certify their compliance to Privacy Shield Principles. AppSheet shall remain liable under the Principles if its agent (third party) processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless AppSheet proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

We may share anonymized, non-personally identifiable usage data with third-party partners to understand, analyze, or explain aggregate customer usage of our service.

## Data Security and Durability

We store user personal information and access tokens in databases hosted by cloud-computing hosting providers. We take reasonable technical steps to protect your information, including the use of passwords, OAuth, secure HTTP, etc. However, we cannot guarantee that your information is immune to a breach in the security and privacy mechanisms implemented by us and the hosting providers. If at any moment a breach of information occurs, we will notify the affected users via email within 72 hours after a confirmed incident.

## Third-Party Sites

Our service provides you with links to third party sites. Once you click on a link to a third-party site, the privacy policy of that third party site is in effect.

## Communication

Our service uses email and other available communication channels to interact with you once you start using AppSheet. These communication channels have their own limitations with respect to message security and privacy, and to the extent your information is communicated on those channels, it is subject to those limitations.

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from AppSheet by following the instructions in those emails. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your AppSheet account, apps, or our ongoing business relationship.

## How we use your information

AppSheet will use your information to:

  * Better communicate with you and maintain a business relationship, and
  * Improve the AppSheet service
  * As required by applicable law, legal process, or regulation.

The information that you provide to us about you will be used to provide better communications and improve our commercial relationship with you. Information about your usage of the platform helps us improve the AppSheet service. We may also use your personal information in response to lawful requests when applicable by law, legal process, or regulation.

Upon request, AppSheet will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. AppSheet retains your data while you are a customer and use our service and will delete your personal information upon written request. You may also send requests about your contact preferences, changes, and deletions to your information including requests to opt-out of sharing your personal information with third parties by emailing [support@appsheet.com](mailto:support@appsheet.com). AppSheet will respond within a reasonable time frame to any request to delete your information. Individuals who have provided information to AppSheet customers through applications created using the AppSheet service must send requests to change or delete such information to the specific AppSheet customer.

## Opting Out

If at any time you are dissatisfied with our service and want to stop being a user (we hope not!), please send an email to [support@appsheet.com](mailto:support@appsheet.com) and we will delete your account. We may retain some information for a reasonable period of time for reporting and auditing purposes. We may retain and utilize your historical non-personally identifiable usage information indefinitely for analysis and learning purposes.

## Contacting AppSheet, Privacy Shield compliance, and Dispute Resolution

We maintain and review an extensive control environment which includes regular training delivered to all our employees on adequate information security policies. Our security policies provide for disciplinary action if our employees fail to follow this Privacy Policy and our Information Security Policy. We periodically review and evaluate these policies for compliance. 

Where applicable, AppSheet is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission.

AppSheet complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. AppSheet has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, AppSheet commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact AppSheet at:

  * Email: [support@appsheet.com](mailto:support@appsheet.com)
  * Postal: SolveBot Inc, 14419 Greenwood Ave N #180, Seattle, WA 98133, USA 

AppSheet has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield> for more information or to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. 

AppSheet commits to cooperate with EU data protection authorities and the Swiss Data Protection and Information Commissioner and complies with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland in the context of employment relationship when applicable. 

As a last resort and in limited situations, EU individuals may seek redress from the [Privacy Shield Panel](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=F-The-Arbitration-Panel), a binding arbitration mechanism.

## California Users

Under California Civil Code Section 1789.3, California users are entitled to the following consumer rights notice:

If you have a question or complaint regarding the site, please send an email to [support@appsheet.com](mailto:support@appsheet.com). You may also contact us by writing to SolveBot Inc, 14419 Greenwood Ave N #180, Seattle, WA 98133, USA, or by calling us at (206) 486-4185. California residents may reach the Complaint Assistance Unit of the Division of Consumer Services of the California Department of Consumer Affairs by mail at 1625 North Market Blvd., Suite N 112, Sacramento, CA 95834, or by telephone at (916) 445-1254 or (800) 952-5210.

## Changes to the Privacy Policy

Our service is evolves rapidly. As our service and product evolve, we may make changes to our privacy policy and reserve the right to do so. If we change this privacy policy, we will make a note of it on our site and send you an email communication with the updates. Your continued use of our service indicates that you agree to our changes.
